Evan Parker

Full Stack Developer (JavaScript, React, Node)

+44(0)7951 994183

evancp@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-parker-9a336987/ London Based

Developer Portfolio: https://github.com/evancp87

I'm a software developer with experience in managing digital projects and a love of problem solving

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING SKILLS

- JavaScript: ES6+, Typescript, AJAX & API's REST and GraphQL, Animation (GSAP), Graphing (D3) & Realtime (Websockets and socket.io), OAuth, Git, Github.
- React: Hooks, context, classes, Material UI, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Toolkit Query, React 19 React Server Components, React Compiler
- Testing: Cypress, Vitest, Vite, Tape, Selenium, Puppeteer, Nightwatch, Jest, Mock Service Worker
- Node.js: Vanilla & Express, Hapi, Next.JS
- Databases: SQL MySQL, NoSQL MongoDB with Mongoose.js, Elastic Search, Redis, Firebase, Supabase, GraphCMS/Hygraph
- DevOps: Docker, Kubernetes, Travis (CI/CD), Vercel (CI/CD), AWS Elastic Beanstalk, serverless (Netlify), Render, cPanel, Apache, XAMPP, Github Actions, Lambda
- CSS 3: Responsive design, Flexbox & Grid, SASS, and CSS frameworks, Tailwind.
- HTML5: Semantically correct for accessibility and SEO.

KEY PROJECTS

Tech Used:

- Front-end: JavaScript, Flickity, Joi, Tape, Sass, Selenium
- Back-end: Node, Elastic Search, Joi, JWTs, Redis

Purpose of project: The Science Museum's popular collections online website, used by hobbyists, researchers and developers. It is an open source web service/api, for developers to use in their applications own, and a front end that allows users to search for 500,000 items from the collection and filter by category.

Title: Science Museum - Barcode Scanner (in development)

Tech Used:

- Front-end: React, TypeScript, Joi
- Back-end: Node, Elastic Search, Joi, JWTs, Redis (uses CO api)

Purpose of project: A barcode scanner for internal use at the Science Museum, to scan collection items and bring up a link to the item on the CO website

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Title: First Level - https://first-level.onrender.com/

Tech Used:

- Front-end: React, RTK, GSAP, Tailwind CSS
- Back-end: Node Express, phpMyAdmin, MySQL, JWTs, Bcrypt

Purpose of project:

A fictional video games e-commerce site that consumes games from the RAWG games database api and allows users to browse games and add to a cart. On registering an account the user can also create and add games to wish lists, as well as search the project database for games.

Title: Reelhub - https://reelhub.vercel.app/

Tech Used:

- Front-end: Next JS, TypeScript, RTK Query, GSAP, Tailwind CSS, Jest, Mock Service Worker
- Back-end: Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, JWTs, Bcrypt, Cloudinary

Purpose of project:

A full stack Netflix inspired clone. The user can register, upload an avatar image, log in and see recommended content, bookmark content and filter content.

EDUCATION

The Jump Digital School

Mar 2023 - Aug 2023

- A 22-week programme of Full-Stack Software Engineering Training
- Training to develop and deploy full-stack web applications to a professional standard
- Delivered individual and team projects, remotely, including participation in a hackathon

General Assembly

May 2012 - July 2021

- Online 10 week intro to Front-End Web Development
- Learned the fundamentals of HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Built small projects, culminating in a final project presented to the cohort at the end of the course

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Science Museum Group

Dec 2023 - Dec 2024

<u>Full Stack Developer</u>

Tech Used: JavaScript, Flickity, Joi, Tape, Sass, Redis, Selenium, Node, ElasticSearch, Joi, JWTs

- Refactored and expanded on the CO 2.0 api and frontend, an SMG collections website of over 500,000 items
- Updated legacy code
- Collaborated with SMG's Digital, Data, and curatorial teams, and other stakeholders
- Worked with the tech lead, frontend developer, and freelance developers
- Developed new frontend components and improved accessibility
- Addressed backlog of bugs
- Built a React barcode scanner app for company internal use
- Worked on a project to integrate generative ai into searches and display records in new ways
- Expanded on an existing suite of unit and end to end tests
- Improved Elastic Search queries to retrieve more accurate results, i.e. dealing with spelling mistakes

Royal Academy of Arts

Sep 2022 - Dec 2023

<u>Digital Product & Infrastructure Team</u>

- Making JavaScript and CSS amendments
- Working with the team stack, including Next JS, React, TypeScript, StoryBook, Ruby, MySQL, ElasticSearch, Sass, Python, and C#.
- End to end, integration and user acceptance testing, including creating test scripts
- Worked on a Bloomberg funded project to rebuild the RA frontend, carrying out rigorous testing and QA
- Prototyping with Figma and Miro
- Working alongside the tech lead, software developers and other stakeholders
- Managing 4 websites for RA, a GUI for an SQL database, a CMS and a Tessitura Network

Oval Design *Jun 2022 - Dec 2022*

Web Developer

- Implementing JavaScript, CSS and HTML to build and deploy sites
- Worked alongside a designer to create visually appealing and performant sites

British Library

Oct 2017 - Sep 2022

Cultural Events Assistant

- Worked with the web development team to develop an event archive space built with React, to showcase he Library's event video material
- Updated the website CMS
- Assisted with the delivery, planning and administration of the Library's Cultural Event's programme

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- I have the right to work in the UK
- Immediately available for interview